<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><REUTERS CGISPLIT="TRAINING-SET" LEWISSPLIT="TRAIN" NEWID="13160" OLDID="2129" TOPICS="NO">
<DATE> 3-APR-1987 16:40:08.56</DATE>
<TOPICS/>
<PLACES><D>usa</D></PLACES>
<PEOPLE/>
<ORGS/>
<EXCHANGES/>
<COMPANIES/>
<UNKNOWN> 
   F
   f2337 reute
u f BC-DRUG-COMPANIES-=6-NEW   04-03 0114</UNKNOWN>
<TEXT TYPE="UNPROC"> 
DRUG COMPANIES =6 NEW YORK
    Hyman said cosmetics used to be more appealing to drug
companies, but product lines have matured and competition
became more fierce. "At one time, the profit margins in these
businesses were more attractive. The businesses were small and
had a lot of opportunity to grow," she said.
    Analysts said drugs, while ultimately subject to patent
expirations, can be marketed for years without competition from
generic products. Cosmetics, however, are fad related and there
are no barriers to competition.
    Saks said pharmaceutical companies in the last two years
have been selling non-strategic assets, among them the once
alluring cosmetics businesses.
    Pfizer Inc &lt;PFE&gt; and Schering-Plough Corp &lt;SGP&gt; remain
among the only two drug companies with cosmetics concerns.
    Schering is committed to its Maybelline cosmetics unit.
    "We've made a strategic determination as a company that
cosmetics is a main line business for us, and we want to
develop it aggressively," the spokesman said. The spokesman
would not comment on whether Schering would want to add by
acquisition to that line.
    Pfizer had no comment, but analyst Ronald Nordmann of
PaineWebber said he does not believe Pfizer would want to sell
off its Coty business.
    Analysts said Elizabeth Arden is one of the more attractive
cosmetics concerns.
    Hyman said the company's performance should be in line with
the expectations for the U.S. industry. She predicts the U.S.
industry in 1987 will have unit growth of three pct and sales
growth of six pct.
    She estimated U.S. cosmetic sales to amount to about two
billion dlrs annually.
    Arden had operating profits of 32.6 mln dlrs in 1986 on
sales of 397.9 mln dlrs.
   
 Reuter
 

</TEXT>
</REUTERS>