<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><REUTERS CGISPLIT="TRAINING-SET" LEWISSPLIT="TRAIN" NEWID="1549" OLDID="17967" TOPICS="NO">
<DATE> 4-MAR-1987 11:38:36.65</DATE>
<TOPICS/>
<PLACES><D>uk</D></PLACES>
<PEOPLE/>
<ORGS/>
<EXCHANGES/>
<COMPANIES/>
<UNKNOWN> 
   RM
   f0703 reute
u f BC-MIDLAND-RIGHTS-ISSUE   03-04 0109</UNKNOWN>
<TEXT TYPE="UNPROC"> 
MIDLAND RIGHTS ISSUE STILL EXPECTED SAY ANALYSTS LONDON, March
4 - Midland Bank Plc's &lt;MDBL.L&gt; 1986 results suggest its shares
show further recovery potential, although a rights issue is
still expected in the next few months, banking analysts said.
    A rights issue of the order of 400 mln stg is seen, perhaps
in June if there is no U.K. General election, they added.
Midland Chairman Sir Donald Barron would not comment on the
rights question at a news conference.
    Earlier, Midland reported 1986 pre-tax profit of 434 mln
stg, up from 351 mln the previous year, in line with market
forecasts, dealers said. Midland shares were up 14p at 633p.
    Midland said its 1986 results included Crocker National
Corp for the first five months, prior to its sale last May. If
results were restated excluding distortions stemming from the
Crocker sale they would show a 1986 pre-tax profit of 432 mln
stg compared with 366 mln, it said.
    Barron said that after the sale of Crocker and
restructuring during the last two years the group had "put the
past firmly behind us in 1986" and was now "focusing our
considerable resources on the exciting opportunities ahead."
    Chief Executive Sir Kit McMahon said U.K. Operations were
the main source of profits, with 83 pct or 434 mln stg.
    Both net interest income and non-interest income were ahead
of 1985.
    A key component in domestic asset growth was a 96 pct rise
in Midland's mortgage portfolio to 2.7 billion stg, comfortably
exceeding a 2.5 billion target, McMahon said. Overall sterling
advances rose over 18 pct to 20.2 billion stg.
    Pre-tax profits in investment banking rose 27 pct to 65 mln
stg despite the heavy start-up and integration costs. However,
this included the group's full range of activities in this area
from its treasuries operations to its merchant bank to
securities and gilts trading activities.
    No breakdown of this figure was given although McMahon said
venture capital activites contributed 17 mln stg to profit. He
said the group's gilts trading was operating at a profit
although its securities activities were not, but would give no
further details.
    International banking profits rose 80 pct to 54 mln stg,
benefitting from past restructuring and good performances from
European subsidiaries.
    Crocker and the Bracton subsidiary created by Midland to
work out Crocker's problem loans made a loss of 44 mln stg in
1986 against a 35 mln loss in 1985.
    Bracton assets now stood at 300 mln dlrs and had been fully
provisioned, McMahon said.
    Charges for bad and doubtful debts declined to 357 mln stg
against 431 mln the previous year and the bank said that
excluding Crocker, it would have been 320 mln.
    McMahon noted that total cover for bad debts had increased
to three pct of lendings in 1986 from 2.6 pct in 1985. He said
no evidence of increasing consumer credit delinquency and fewer
U.K. Corporate defaults allowed for a lower domestic debt
charge in 1986.
    McMahon said Midland's exposure in South America remained
unchanged on 1985, with 1.4 billion stg outstanding to Brazil,
1.3 billion to Mexico and 600 mln to Argentina.
    Following the lead of the other four major U.K. Banks
Midland moved charges against lending to rescheduling countries
from general to specific provisions.
    This was the key factor behind a reduction in its tax rate
to just under 40 pct in 1986 from 59 pct in 1985, McMahon said.
    One major problem still to be faced by the bank was to
further reduce its cost/income ratio, which is still well above
its competitors at 72 pct, he added.
 REUTER
 

</TEXT>
</REUTERS>