<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><REUTERS CGISPLIT="TRAINING-SET" LEWISSPLIT="TRAIN" NEWID="12395" OLDID="1471" TOPICS="YES">
<DATE> 2-APR-1987 01:08:04.55</DATE>
<TOPICS><D>acq</D></TOPICS>
<PLACES><D>west-germany</D></PLACES>
<PEOPLE/>
<ORGS/>
<EXCHANGES/>
<COMPANIES/>
<UNKNOWN> 
   RM
   f0043 reute
u f BC-DEUTSCHE-AGREES-FULL   04-02 0097</UNKNOWN>
<TEXT> 
<TITLE>DEUTSCHE AGREES FULL TAKEOVER OF FORMER EURASBANK</TITLE>
<DATELINE>    FRANKFURT, April 2 - </DATELINE><BODY>Deutsche Bank AG &lt;DBKG.F&gt; has agreed
to take over the outstanding 25 pct in &lt;Deutsche Bank (Asia)
AG&gt;, the former &lt;European Asian Bank AG&gt;, from
Creditanstalt-Bankverein &lt;CABV.VI&gt;, Deutsche management board
joint spokesman Alfred Herrhausen told a news conference.
    Euras broke even in 1986 and required no funding from
Deutsche, he said. He gave no details of the deal with
Creditanstalt.
    Press reports that Deutsche was planning a takeover of
Lloyds Bank plc &lt;LLOY.L&gt; were without foundation, he said.
    Herrhausen said Deutsche had taken part in the recent
capital increase of &lt;Morgan Grenfell Group plc&gt;, but had no
plans to raise its 4.4 pct share in Morgan Grenfell.
    &lt;Banca d'America e d'Italia SpA&gt;, in which 98.3 pct was
acquired from Bankamerica Corp &lt;BAC.N&gt; late last year, would be
consolidated this year, and contribute to further expansion of
Deutsche's business, management board joint spokesman F.
Wilhelm Christians said.
    Following a ruling earlier this year from the Federal High
Court, Deutsche had included its non-bank holdings in the
balance sheet section "participations," Christians said.
    But Christians said the bank still regarded shares in these
non-bank companies as an investment rather than an active
participation.
    Parent bank total participations rose to 6.45 billion marks
in 1986 from a comparable 4.57 billion in 1985 including a rise
to 3.79 billion from 2.34 billion in bank participations.
    Herrhausen said the grouping of holdings in the balance
sheet in this was was not a first step to floating them off in
a separate holding company.
 Reuter
 </BODY></TEXT>
</REUTERS>